Guide to the Bernard Aresu Academic Papers, 1983-2013, UA 404 UA 404
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Bernard Aresu Academic Papers
1983-2013
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Aresu, Bernard, 1944-
UA 404
4 Linear Feet 4 boxes
The papers document Dr. Aresu's teaching career at Rice University during the years of 1983 to 2013.
Biographical / Historical
Bernard Aresu, the Laurence F. Favrot Professor of French and Professor Emeritus at Rice University, received his License de Lettres from the Universite de Montpelier, France in 1967 and a Ph.D. from the University of Washington in 1975. His teaching and research interests are in comparative and transnational literary studies in the 20th and 21st centuries with special focus on cultures of the global south. He joined the Rice faculty in 1997 and has served as Master for Brown and Lovett (2004-2009) residential colleges.
Scope and Contents
The papers document Dr. Aresu's teaching career at Rice University during the years of 1983 to 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research except for restricted access to Faculty/Graduate student candidates, Recommendations, Staff editorial assistant and Humanities Dean search.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were transferred to the university archives by Dr. Aresu on June 26, 2018.
Arrangement
The collections is arranged in alphabetical files, with sub-series of Budgets, Courses, Faculty, Graduate Studies.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; French literature; Faculty; Education
Places
Rice University
- Series I: Alphabetical files
  - Advertising/outreach, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alliance Francaise, 1994-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumni, 1998, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual reports, 1983-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual reports, 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arabic studies, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Awards: Commencement, 1998-99, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Awards, grants, fellowships, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sub-series A: Budgets
    - Annual departmental, 1980s, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Faculty summer research, 1997-2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Graduate Studies stipends, 1997-2003 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Graduate students, 1997-2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Buildings, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Calendars (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Career Services Center, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Cavalier de la Salle, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Club Chouette (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Colleges, residential, 1998, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Consulat de France, 1999-2003 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Consulat research materials (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Consulat PLFS proposal final, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Continuing education, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Development, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Distribution, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Evaluations, 1998-2003 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Sub-series B: Courses
    - FLAC, 1998-2002 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - French (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - French 100, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - French 200, 1987, 1990s, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
    - French 301, 1980s, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - French 302, 1980s, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - French 303, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - French 305, 1995-1998, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - French 311, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - French 312, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - French 324, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - French 336, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - French 425, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - French for engineers, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - French course descriptions (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - General Announcements (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Humanities 102, 1999, 2000s (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Numbering, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Proposals, summer, 1994-2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Dartmouth, 2003-2009 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ethnic studies, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Sub-series C: Faculty
    - French Renaissance scholar, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Hiring, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Hiring: Early Modern, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Leaves, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Faculty/graduate candidates
      - Abdel-Jaooad, Hedi (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Anagnostopovlou, Maria (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Bahmanyar, Piraye (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Bensmaia, Reda (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Blais, Marie (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Bolduc, Benoit (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Bourjea, Serge (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Darras, Eugenia (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Erickson, John (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Ershova, Eugenia (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Frederick, Patricia (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Gackowski-Gayer, Marila (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Gadjigo, Samba (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Gracki, Katherine (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Guchu, Lois (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Irele, Francis (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Ji, Zhen (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Kilpatrick, James (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - King, Roger (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Leduc, Natali (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Leverson, Corinne (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Marx-Scouras, Danielle (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Nelson, Deborah (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Reynolds, Felisa (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Robin, Jean-Luc (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Rozwarski, Mickael (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Salaberry, Rafael (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Shea, Louisa (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Smith, Marie-Christine (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Stoka, Madaline (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Stranges, Peter (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Toumi, Alek (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Tysor, Susannah (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Zheng, Lu (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Ziethen, Antje (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Misc. (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    - Ferguson-Bull endowment (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - French business symposium (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - French departmental (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
    - French departmental meeting minutes (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - French studies/graduate studies (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
    - French Ph.D. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - General announcements (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Graduate student placement (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Sub-series D: Graduate Studies
    - Advertising (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Alumni (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Reading list (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Recruiting, 2001 forward (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Recruiting abroad (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Regulations, departmental (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Regulations, university (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Humanities dean search, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Lectures (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Italian Studies (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Language placement tests (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Library [Fondren] (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Martinique campus [?] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Merging conversations (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Pi Delta Phi, 1997, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Plays, French (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Recommendations (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Rennes Universite info (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Rennes Universite, 1985-1998 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rennes Universite, 1999 - (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Review, School of Humanities, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Staff editorial assistant, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Study of Women and Gender, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Undergraduate business problems, 1987, 1990s, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Undergraduate Curriculum Committee, 2008, 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Undergraduate majors (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Undergraduate questionnaire, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Undergraduate studies (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - University-related, 2001 - (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Washington, University of, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Writing programs, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 29)